Guide to the Jessica Burstein Photographs and Memorabilia 1940s-2017 (bulk 1970s-2012) PR 361
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Law & Order, 1993-circa 2008; 10.6 Linear feet
  - Documents. "Play Dead: The Law & Order Crime Scene Book", circa 2003 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Proposal for the crime scenes book.
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes" Text Drafts (2 folders), 1997, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    Holds various drafts of the text (circa 2003) and a partial list from NBC of summaries of shows shown in 1997.
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes." Mock-up for Chapter 2, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes.", 2003 (Box 16)
    Book as published, but without covers.
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes", 2003 (Box 16)
    A copy of the book as published.
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes" Photo Logs, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Documents. "Law & Order: Crime Scenes." Miscellaneous, 2003, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Three documents: a full page ad for the book in the New York Times; photocopy of a 1988 police report; reproduction of the script for the opening teaser of the episode "Oxymoron" of 2002; and publicity for a related exhibition at the Hudson River Museum (2005).
  - Documents. Law & Order. Cast, Crew and Set, 2005-2009 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Four documents: Season 15 2nd Yellow Final Crew List (2005); Pre-production schedule (13 September 2007); memo from Fred Berner re: "Season 18: The Revolutionary Evolution of Law & Order" (2008?); and crew call, signed by Sam Waterston (12 March 2009).
  - Documents. Law & Order Miscellaneous, 2004, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    Five documents: a holiday party invitation (2004); a holiday card from Wolf Films (with a photo by Burstein) signed by Dick Wolf; a Special Collector's Issue of TV Guide on the occasion of Law & Order's 20th anniversary, with photos by Burstein and a specific section about her work on the set (2009); an Art Department Master List (undated); and an envelope with Law & Order/Wolf Films mailing label.
  - Documents. Law & Order: Criminal Intent. Crew and Set, 2006-2009 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Five documents: Display permit(?) from New York City Mayor's Office for Season 5 filming; Yellow crew lists (Seasons 7 and 10); and Pink crew lists (Seasons 7 and 8).
  - Documents. Law & Order: Criminal Intent. Still Photo Shoot Requirements, 2007 February-April (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Documents. Law & Order: Criminal Intent. Full Pink Script for Episode "Trophy Wine", 2011 March 6 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Documents. Law & Order: Criminal Intent. Book: "Last Looks: Season Ten", 2011 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Book with photographs and text by Burstein memorializing the cast and crew of Season 10. Signed by Burstein.
  - Poster: Exiled: A Law & Order Movie, [1999] (Folder FF-2)
    Burstein captioned on back "My poster for Exiled (N.Y. shots)" April 2018. Approx 24x30. Flattened by Alan Balicki, April 2018.
  - Memorabilia. "Hot Set" Sign, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    Painted cardboard sign, presumably from the show set.
  - Memorabilia. Stage crew safety sign from set (Flat box), undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia. Tee Shirts & Caps, circa 1999-2005 (Box 29)
    Six tee shirts (three related to Criminal Intent, one from the movie Exiled, two others related to the Law & Order crew); nine caps (two commemorating the 250th and 300th episodes; five labeled for the Special Victims Unit seasons 1999-2000 through 2002-2003, and the 100th episode in 2003-2004; two labeled for the Criminal Intent show); and a throw pillow. One of the caps has a thank you tag signed by executive producer Dick Wolf and others.
  - Memorabilia. Police Tape, circa 2005 (Box 29)
    One roll of yellow crime scene tape made for the exhibition at George Eastman House.
  - Memorabilia. ID cards, 2000s (Box 26)
    Two of Burstein's ID cards for the "Law & Order" set.
- Series IV. New York Undercover, 1994-1997; 1.3 Linear feet
  The series includes cast and set photographs from the Fox network TV show New York Undercover, which ran from 1994-1999 and, like "Law & Order," was produced by Dick Wolf. Cast members and guest stars found in this collection include, among others, Malik Yoba, Michael DeLorenzo, Clarence Williams III, Gladys Knight, Erykah Badu, Teddy Pendergrass, Bobby Brown, Boyz II Men, George Benson, Ben Vereen. The bulk are 11x14 inches, with some 8x10. A small number are in color. There are many duplicate prints. Most are uncaptioned. Identified, dated, or otherwise annotated photographs are at front of box.
  The photographs are held in one box in no particular order, generally as received from the photographer.
  - New York Undercover Photographs, 1994-1997 (Box 17)
- Series V. Sunny Atlantic Beach Club / Atlantic Beach Book, 2006, 2012; 1.8 Linear feet
  The series consists of a portfolio of color 11x14 photographs taken at the club in Atlantic Beach, Long Island (one photo dated 2006, the others are undated), a self-published book that includes images of the club and other beach scenes (2012), and a few loose, related images found elsewhere in the collection during processing.
  The portfolio, book and some loose photos are held in one box, with a few larger size photos held in a separate box.
  - Sunny Atlantic Beach Club / Atlantic Beach Book, 2006, 2012 (Box 18)
  - Beach Club Photographs (Flat box), circa 2006 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    Four copies of the above photographs, size 22x17 inches.
- Series VI. Various Subjects, 1940s-2017 (bulk 1970s-1990s); 8.1 Linear feet
  The series holds primarily black and white photographs across a range of subject matter. To a large degree it appears that these photographs date from the 1970s and were likely taken by Burstein in connection with her work as a photographer for NBC. In this context, much of the content includes NBC television sports and news announcers, talk show hosts, TV show actors and actresses, as well as musicians, political figures and events, and others.
  The series also holds some photos from before Burstein's time at NBC, including anti-war demonstrations of about 1971. More photos date from the late 1970s and up to 2017, and include various celebrities from the sports, entertainment and literary worlds. There are also sets of photographs of business families, likely done by Burstein on a commission basis. Most of the photographs center on people, but there are a few New York City views. It also seems likely that there are some photographs here from the New York Undercover television series and from Elaine's Restaurant that were not boxed separately by the photographer and were not recognizable as such by the processing archivist.
  Because of the broad range of subjects, the container list below includes more specifics as to the content.
  In addition to photographs the series includes a few documents, mostly related to Burstein's photo assignments. These include a small number of NBC call sheets and cast lists; similar documents related to the filming of John Cassavetes's movie "Gloria"; and teletypes reporting the resignation of Richard Nixon from the presidency.
  Finally, the series holds various items of memorabilia, including tee shirts and political and other pins.
  The series is arranged first by format: photographs, followed by documents and memorabilia.
  The photographs are arranged by subject matter. When presented to N-YHS most of the photographs in this series were in no particular order. The processing archivist arranged them into categories and particular subjects. The sequence as see in the container list below is roughly as follows: NBC photographs specifically identified as such by Burstein; NBC telecasts and on-air personalities; political matters (demonstrations, conventions, activists, politicians); sports figures; entertainers; business, literary and other figures; and miscellaneous portraits, street scenes, etc.
  - NBC Studios Photographs (8x10), 1940s-1960 (Box 24)
    7 historical photos from NBC: the National Broadcasting Company Election Chart of 1948, showing Dewey conceding at 11:12 AM, with NBC tabulators; John F. Kennedy and Richard M. Nixon debate of 1960 (2); Bud Abbott and Lou Costello on a NBC radio broadcast; Bob Hope and Frank Sinatra on a NBC radio broadcast; Howdy Doody puppet and show, circa 1957 (2).
  - NBC Studios Photographs (8x10), 1974-1979 (Box 24)
    Photos released by NBC dating from the 1970s, which were presumably taken by Burstein. Information from the NBC Press Department is included with each photo, which relate to upcoming NBC-TV shows. All are 7x9 inches, black and white. Shows represented include:
    1974: actress Audrey Landers of "Somerset"; Rita Moreno at Nathan's of Coney Island for a "Go" segment; Freddie Prinze of "Chico and the Man" in Washington Heights; birth of a baby for a "Go" segment; several photos related to the 3-hour news special "Of Women and Men" dealing with the transformation in their social and cultural relationships.
    1975: Lee Richardson as Jonathan Edwards in "A Gathering of One"; announcers Bobby Riggs and Julie Heldman and women tennis players in connection with the Family Circle Cup; Iman for a "Weekend" segment.
    1976: Richard Chamberlain in "The Man in the Iron Mask."
    1977: Annette O'Toole and Richard Crenna in "The War Between the Tates"; Paul Simon for a music special; Shirley Jo Finney and Cicely Tyson in "Wilma"; Robert Powell and others in "The Four Feathers."
    1978: Various scenes from "Black Beauty"; Cicely Tyson and Paul Winfield portraying Coretta Scott King and Martin Luther King, Jr., in "King."
    1979: Louis Gossett Jr. and others in "Lawman Without a Gun."
  - NBC-TV Miniseries "King", circa 1978 (Box 19)
    Photos of Paul Winfield, Cicely Tyson and others on set of film concerning Martin Luther King, Jr.
  - NBC-TV News & Sports Announcers & Guests, 1970s (Box 19)
    Ed Newman, John Chancellor, David Brinkley, Barbara Walters, Chuck Scarborough, Joe Garagiola, Tim Ryan, Tom Snyder (including one on top of "30 Rock"), and others, with guests Henry Kissinger and others.
  - Frank Field (meteorologist) & Winston the Weather Dog, circa 1976 (Box 19)
  - Johnny Carson, circa 1970s (Box 19)
  - Jimmy Carter & Barbara Walters, 1976? (Box 19)
    Mostly behind the scenes shots of Carter sitting on floor chatting with Walters and her daughter. Also a photo of Carter's wife, Rosalynn, with Cornelia Wallace.
  - Anti-War Protests (including Vietnam), circa 1971 (Box 19)
  - Anti-Nuclear Arms/Disarmament Rally, New York City, 1982 (Box 25)
  - Protests & Political Statements (other than anti-war), 1970s-2000s (Box 19)
    Photographs of various demonstrations on political matters (against Rockefeller drug laws, for George Wallace for president, March on Hunger, free political prisoners, against George W. Bush, and others). Some images appear to be related to political protest though this is not explicit nor certain.
  - Activists, 1970s (Box 19)
    Julian Bond*, Ralph Abernathy*, Ramsey Clark*, Jane Fonda, Betty Friedan, Jesse Jackson, Coretta Scott King, Ralph Nader*, Gloria Steinem. *Some of these photos appear to have been taken in the context of NBC programs, specifically the miniseries "King" and "Saturday Night Live" (SNL).
  - Democratic Conventions, 1968-1992 (Box 19)
    Includes photographs of individual delegates, general convention floor shots, candidates/political figures, and candidate or protest signage.
  - New York Political Figures, 1972-1990s (Box 19)
    Karen Burstein (photographer's sister, running for office), Beatrice Burstein (photographer's mother and NY Supreme Court Justice), Shirley Chisholm, Abe Beame, Mario Cuomo, Basil Patterson, Herman Badillo, John Lindsay (at Earl Wilson birthday party), Ed Koch, Bella Abzug, and other local judges and officials.
  - Political Figures Other than New York, 1968-1990s? (Box 19)
    Edmund Muskie, John Tunney, George McGovern, Lloyd Bentsen, Bill Bradley, Tip O'Neill (one with Hugh Carey), Scoop Jackson, John Lewis, Gene McCarthy, George Wallace, Richard Daley, Hillary Clinton, John McCain, Sandra Day O'Connor, Yitzhak Rabin.
  - Sports Figures: Baseball, Boxing, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 20)
    Reggie Jackson, George Steinbrenner, Yogi Berra, Willie Mays (with Mets), Sugar Ray Leonard, George Foreman, Jose Torres, Muhammad Ali (and with Bill White).
  - Sports Figures: Basketball, circa 1990s (Box 20)
    Wilt Chamberlain, Patrick Ewing
  - Sports Figures: Tennis, circa 1970s (Box 20)
    Chris Evert, Billie Jean King, Bobby Riggs, Stan Smith, Arthur Ashe, John McEnroe
  - Marlon Brando, circa 1979 (Box 20)
  - Marlon Brando, 1979 (Folder FF-3)
    Approx 20x22, signed, on foamcore. Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.
  - Red Buttons, circa 1970s (Box 20)
  - Cast Photographs: "Saturday Night Live" (SNL), circa 1970s (Box 20)
    John Belushi, Steve Martin, Gilda Radner, Lily Tomlin, Ralph Nader, Julian Bond, Chevy Chase, Laraine Newman, George Carlin, Paul Simon
  - Cast Photographs: Miscellaneous, circa 1978-1995 (Box 20)
    Lou Gossett ("Lawman without a Gun)?; Tony Bennett & Cicely Tyson (("King"?); Dean Martin Comedy Hour; Aida Turturro & Tom Conti ("Wright Verdicts", 1995); Meryl Streep & James Woods ("Holocaust" miniseries, 1978).
  - Bill Cosby, circa 1970s (Box 20)
  - Jacques D'Amboise, circa 1970s? (Box 20)
    Dancing poses with unidentified woman.
  - Senta Driver, circa 1980 (Box 25)
  - Doug Henning & Julie Newmar, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Gladys Knight & Tom T. Hall, 1974? (Box 20)
  - Jerry Lewis, circa 1970s (Box 20)
  - Bruce Morrow ("Cousin Brucie") Montage, circa 1970s (Folder FF-2)
  - Hugh O'Brian Hosting "Model of the Year" Contest, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Bert Parks & Phyllis George, 1970s (Box 20)
    Miss America Pageant co-hosts
  - Freddie Prinze, circa 1976 (Box 20)
  - Don Rickles (and others). Award Ceremony (8x10), 1970s (Box 25)
  - Paul Simon and others (Box 20)
    Photographs of Paul Simon taken over time. Also includes Simon with Art Garfunkel, and Garfunkel alone; with Chevy Chase; with George Harrison; and with Phoebe Snow.
  - Tommy Tune, 1980s? (Box 25)
  - Harry Winston. 80th Birthday Party, 1977? (Box 20)
  - Wolfman Jack, circa 1970s (Box 20)
  - Entertainers/Entertainment Industry. Miscellaneous, 1970s-1999 (Box 20)
    One or two photographs of: Desi Arnaz, Pierce Brosnan, James Brown (singer), Tony Bennett, George Benson, Roscoe Lee Brown, Scatman Crothers, Paddy Chayefsky, Mariska Hargitay, Faye Dunaway, Leon Fleicher, Rosemary Harris, James Earl Jones (1983), Alan King, Rich Little, Keb Mo, Randy Newman, Chris Noth, Billy Preston, Tony Roberts, Nipsey Russell, Brooke Shields, Sissy Spacek, Abe Vigoda, Jon Voight, Forrest Whitaker (1999).
  - Entertainers/Entertainment Industry. Miscellaneous (8x10), circa 1970s (Box 25)
    Tom T. Hall, George Edwards (game show host), The Four Tops, Al Green, Sue Lyon, Donny and Marie Osmond, Rita Moreno, Melvin Van Peebles, cast of TV-show "Muggsy"
  - Publicity Pieces. Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-2000s (Box 20)
    Stri-Dex ad; 4 stills from a video about baseball (fans); demo montage of portraits for Harry Walker Agency.
  - Publicity Pieces. Miscellaneous (8x10), 1970s-1987 (Box 25)
    Montage for celebration for benefit chairwoman Kitty Ault (1987), cast of "How to Pick Up Girls" (1979); Marsha Mason and Neil Simon in "Only When I Laugh": Frederick's of Hollywood (1970s).
  - John Cage, 1982 (Folder FF-3)
    Approx 18x25, signed, on foamcore. Unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018.
  - Truman Capote, circa 1979 (Box 21)
  - Tom Carvel (ice cream franchise business), 1978 (Box 21)
  - Nicholas D'Agostino and Sons (supermarket business), 1980s? (Box 21)
  - Eileen Ford & Family (Ford Modeling Agency), circa 1980s? (Box 21)
  - Sam Goody & Sons (music retail business), circa 1980s (Box 21)
  - Ironworkers on Park Avenue Waiting for Jobs, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Kennedy Airport Chaplain, 1980s (Box 25)
  - Norman Mailer. 50th Birthday Party, 1973? (Box 20)
  - Ned Moran & Son (Moran Towing), circa 1980s (Box 21)
    On company tugboat
  - LeRoy Neiman, circa 1970s-1994 (Box 21)
  - Paris Review Party, 1973 (Box 25)
  - Sardi Family (restaurateurs), 1980s (Box 21)
  - Charles Scribner & Son (publishing business), circa 1970s (Box 21)
  - Identified Portraits. Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-2017 (Box 21)
    One or two photographs of: Douglas Adams (author), Sarah Bone? (Lakota Sioux), Kofi Annan, Bartholomew I (Archbishop of Constantinople), Art Buchwald, Judd Burstein (photographer's brother), Barbara Gordon (author), Elizabeth Griffin, Billy Graham, Pete Hamill, Charles Kipps (producer), Lewis Lapham, J.W. Marriott, Marsha Norman, Tillie Sobel (photographer's grandmother), John Sculley, Paul Stewart family (clothiers), Rex Reed, Salman Rusdie, William Styron, Gay and Nan Talese walking outside Donohue's Steak House (autographed by both, 2017), Taki Theodoracopulos (journalist, 1995),Donald Trump (2, color, one at desk, one at new Yankee Stadium?, circa 2000s), Carl Bernstein (journalist, 1980).
  - Unidentified Portraits, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 21)
    Includes several photographs of individuals that were not identified during processing, but seem likely to be identifiable.
  - New York City Street Scenes, 1970s-2005 (Box 21)
    General views of people, buildings, views. Those that are particularly identifiable or captioned are: view from upper floor of New Yorker Hotel; South Bronx man; Pan Am building; corner of Madison avenue and East 65th street; Coney Island giant lollipop vendor; two Central Park in winter (color), including one of ice skating with Christo's Gates in background; buildings at corner of Amsterdam avenue and West 72nd street.
  - Portraits and Views. Miscellaneous (Box 21)
    Several photographs of people, objects, views, etc. that are not identifiable or that appear to be from outside New York City.
  - Animals, circa 1970s?-2000s (Box 21)
  - Various Subjects (Flat box, 2 folders), 1975-2006 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
    Two matted photographs: Jessica Burstein self-portrait with Arthur Ashe (1975), and Wilt Chamberlain (1997); both unframed by Alan Balicki, April 2018. Other photographs 22x17 inches, generally identical or similar to those in smaller sizes above. SPORTS: Wilt Chamberlain (1997); POLITICAL: Sandra Day O'Connor; ENTERTAINMENT: Tony Bennett, Marlon Brando, James Brown, Faye Dunaway, Jon Secada; WRITERS: Truman Capote, Norman Mailer Party, William Styron, Gay & Nan Talese; ANIMALS: Dog in blanket on Madison avenue (2006); NYC Scenes: Sculpture at World Trade Center (1980s), ice skating at Wollman Rink in Central Park, Christo's "Gates" in background (2005).
  - Poster: "Judge Karen Burstein for Attorney General", 1994 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    From Democratic primary campaign. Approx 18x23.
  - Document. "Stop the Draft" Rally Flyer, 1971? (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Documents. President Richard Nixon Resignation, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Photographs of television screens with the broadcast of Nixon's resignation and Gerald Ford and wife after swearing-in ceremony. Also teletype reports of resignation from Helen Thomas (UPI), Janet Staihar (AP), Gene Carlson, and others unattributed.
  - Documents. NBC Films. Call Sheets & Cast/Crew Info, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Call sheet and set scene summary for "Lawman Without a Gun"; Call sheet and crew/cast lists for "The Four Feathers"; call sheet for "Black Beauty"; and notes from a meeting that appear to be related to union contract negotiations.
  - Documents. Film "Gloria" / "One Summer Night", 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    Call sheets, publicity images, final cast list, staff & crew list, "American Film" magazine with related article, and newsletter for Local 644 of the International Photographers of the Motion Picture Industries. Film was released as "Gloria," but working title was "One Summer Night."
  - Memorabilia. Tee Shirts & Skull Cap, 1970s-2008 (Box 30)
    17 T-shirts: 4 related to the NBC network (Midnight Special with Wolfman Jack; union strikers' shirt; NBC sports/Jets; NBC logo). 6 related to political matters (Bobby Sands, 1954-81, "I have the spirit of freedom"; Solidarnosc/Solidarity; Karen Burstein for Congress; Carol Bellamy for Council President; anti-nuclear bombs (12 June 1982); "The Arkansas Party 1992" [Bill Clinton campaign]). 7 others ("New York Undercover"; Fire Department; "Have Fun with People" [magazine]; page from real estate section of New York Post (12 June 1987); Hands Across America (25 May 1986); American Bicentennial; International Cinematographers Guild, Local 600). 1 skullcap labeled "Obama '08"
  - Memorabilia. Pins, ID Cards, etc., circa 1960-2010 (Box 26)
    About 25 campaign pins for Beatrice Burstein for judicial positions and Karen Burstein for state senator and Congress (many duplicates).
    Jessica Burstein NBC employee ID card (1975); cigarette lighter with NBC sports logo; National Academy of Television Arts & Sciences Pin and luggage tag.
    About 17 Presidential campaign pins (JFK, LBJ, McCarthy, McGovern, Carter, anti-George H.W. Bush, Dukakis, Kerry, Obama).
    About 18 pins related to other political campaigns from New York City and state (Lowenstein, Abzug, Goodell, O'Dwyer, Bellamy, others). 3 pins related to political campaigns generally (1980, 1992, undated).
    About 12 pins concerning anti-war (some refer to or imply Vietnam) and disarmament/anti-nuclear weapons.
    4 pins concerning women's rights.
    6 pins concerning various issues, some obscure: "Free Joe Doherty," March on Hunger; first Earth Day (1970); "Enough," "Where is Ken Starr when you need him?" "I love a clean New York"
    10 pins on various subjects: Nashville souvenir; "Godzilla vs. Megalon"; "Z: He lives"; "Do it in Kentucky"; ICP exhibition; "Chico and the Man" TV show; NBC 1973; movie "Silver City"; "Meet the Press"; World's Fair key chain tag.
    4 Shell Oil Company lapel pins/tie tacks.
  - Memorabilia. Adlai Stevenson Campaign Pin, 1950s (Box 28, Folder 10)